Carl McGee

Minnetonka, Minnesota

Phone: 952-693-8217| Email: Carl.Jack.McGee@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/carl-mcgee-3b9648a0/| Portfolio: https://carljmcgee.github.io/carls-react-portfolio/

Summary

Junior full stack developer with a background in public health. Experienced in mobile-first, user-friendly web applications. Experienced using creative problem solving and communicating with peers to diagnose and fix issues as they arise. Recently earned a certificate in full stack development from the University of Minnesota.

TECHNICAL SKILLS.

Software: VS Code, TRPC, NextAuth, Postman, GraphQL Playground, Browser Developer Tools

Websites: Github, Gitlab, Heroku, Vercel, Planetscale, MongoAtlas

Tech Stacks: T3 Stack, MERN

CSS-in-JS: Bootstrap, Bulma, Tailwind

Software Languages: HTML 5, CSS, Java/Type Script, JQuery, React, Next.js, Prisma, SQL

Projects

Movie Night Randomizer |

https://github.com/CarlJMcGee/movie-picker | https://shit-screen-movie-picker.vercel.app/

Description: A site for organizing my movies for my friends to see what I have available and add movies to a wish list for me to find and purchase later. Movie details are taken from IMDB. By logging in with Discord, you can vote for an available movie and the site will pick a random film for us to watch.

My Contribution: The project was created and is maintained by myself.

Tools Used: Made using the T3 Stack (Typescript, Tailwind, TRPC, Prisma, Next.js, NextAuth) and

Bootstrap React

Neighborhood chat/social site

https://github.com/CarlJMcGee/Geo-Chat Neighborhood-group-chat | https://geo-chat-neighborhoods.herokuapp.com/homepage

Description: A site for locals to connect and socialize online with the people living around them. Sign up with your city name and be automatically added to your neighborhood's homepage **My Contribution:** Worked on the database design and implementation as well as the API endpoints

Tools Used: Made using Vanilla Javascript, Express, and Handlebars.

Avatar Legends TTRPG online character sheet

https://github.com/CarlJMcGee/Avatar-Legends-character-sheet | https://carlimcgee.github.io/Avatar-Legends-character-sheet/

Description: An unofficial online character sheet alternative for the Avatar the Last Airbender

tabletop RPG by Magpie Games.

My Contribution: The project was designed and created by myself **Tools Used:** Made using Vanilla Javascript, Express, and Handlebars.

Experience

Automation Specialist

February 2021 - Present

Memorial Blood Center

St. Paul, Minnesota

- Performing physical examinations of donor vitals and reviewing medical history to determine fitness to donate
- Quickly and carefully prepare and label donation bags and equipment
- Setting up automated donations machines and performing venipunctures for Whole Blood, Double Red Cell, and Plasma donations using aseptic technique
- Responding to donor adverse reactions during or after the donation procedure
- Creating positive donor experiences through good customer service and a comfortable environment to promote repeat donations

Lead Phlebotomist/ Lead Donor Center Technician/Designated Trainer

September 2017 - January 2021

Grifols Talecris Plasma Resources

West St. Paul, Minnesota

- Organized and moved staff to critical areas as needed
- Ensured staff were getting consistent breaks and advocating employee issues to management
- Trained new and cross-training employees and helped them perform at expected levels
- Registered applicant donors into the system and reviewed them for deferrable items
- Set up apheresis machines with disposable softgoods and prepared donors for venipuncture and performed venipunctures for plasma donation

 Monitoring donor condition during the donation process and responding to donor safety issues and emergencies

End-User Technology Associate

January 2017 - August 2017

Ameriprise Financial

Minneapolis, Minnesota

- Reviewed and ensured security compliance in Microsoft Enterprise products
- Recorded software changes to the digital infrastructure
- Assisted in the development and deployment of Microsoft Outlook desktop and mobile in the Microsoft Business 365 Suite
- Reviewed trends in service desk requests for Microsoft Outlook desktop and mobile
- Tested new features and security updates to Outlook prior to End-User deployment
- Assisted End-Users with new features and changes

Education

Certificate: University of Minnesota | Minneapolis, Minnesota

February 2022 - August 2022

An intensive 6 month program focused on full stack web development in Javascript. The course covered basic front-end HTML 5, CSS, and Javascript all the way through full stack single page React apps with the MERN stack.